right haze copies so yeah is it did it
rotate did the whole thing okay cool no
I didn't do this so we got out we got a
neon right up here on the dashboard
I like all probably the other way
no it'll it'll get better in a minute
let's say Hina this gopis there's calm
employees everywhere here we're taking
over this town
frozen easy to eat frozen as it's still
frozen the reception here just isn't
really good is that my yuan enough no no
your Yan is getting shipped out today
probably if you got an email yesterday
your yan ships today
yes pros okay it's a lot better now all
right all right well let's let's wait
till we get on the the road and then we
have some exciting announcements very
exciting so it'll hold now if I engage
ya know closely
oh yeah yeah but the more they're least
not using the model okay so guys a bunch
of exciting things happen today Eddie
got a promotion
um Eddie is now VP of hardware and the
reason why he's VP of hardware is
because he's figure out how to
procedural eyes so you have this thing
you have companies you have like like
like think of like old-school
Aeronautics companies like like like
Boeing or Lockheed they managed to
produce incredible products with
mediocre people yeah I gotta make this
toning advantage
and the way that they do this is through
procedure well I mean he had Lehrer
terrible oh yeah
so remember how I promised that we were
gonna port to all those Toyotas I lied
you're gonna pour it to all the Toyotas
and also we have a new name for you guys
it's not team common anymore I really
figured out what it was today you guys
are the common army
we really are we're an army like like
when I talk about winning who wins I
mean a team can win but who really wins
an army you guys are the comma army and
what we're going to release with this
Corolla is a guide on exactly how we did
this point but it has a leader
um we're gonna release a guide on
exactly how we did this Toyota port so
you guys can follow it up in in a whole
there's like twelve Toyota's that can be
supported there's like another six
Lexuses that can be supported there's no
way we're gonna support all eighteen but
what we are gonna do is ship that's not
that loud we're gonna ship really clean
refactor code and we're gonna ship a
guide so everybody out here watching
those periscopes who has a Toyota will
be able to literally port their own car
so if you have a bigger big Dan Carlin
fan they askin any questions yes we are
set I school in turn of course we yeah
yeah yeah the what call a model oh it
said any call a model except I am
think that's bad for the car the noise
ah it's okay
I think it's okay even a wee little
pudding background loud even wood no
coding background so here's the thing
you guys you're all in the Kama army
right you're all and that's sense I mean
that's really you know like lo gangjae
crawlers kama army um the way that we're
gonna start hiring is basically this you
can't you work up the ranks through the
Kama army you start out as a shell you
start out on slack
you start out submitting pull requests
doing car parts work your way up anybody
can become a general in the kama army so
this is a real vloggers yet yeah but
what we're gonna do is we're gonna
really commit this year to making it
easier for you guys to making it easier
to meaningfully contribute um one of the
things like that keyboard bug right like
there's a keyboard bug the first time
you install up and pile it on oh really
[Music]
accelerate right now stop and go oh
that's too bad
pay attention guys
I'm stat is bottle failure
yeah fancy anything the camera
that's working pretty well
that's all we never change it it's a
dick okay what I want to you want to
challenge it because of the steadiness
no it's because so basically the this
car is lighter and so the same amount of
torque is actually feels way more and so
there is this safety code about how much
Delta torque we allow between driver and
and toward that we can commander so when
you do it like I make I made the change
in control or gonna make the change in
in safety I think we need to do it I
think it's bad so if you hold it and you
release it you would feel like the car
faster come Pacific control is just much
better about this but yeah so so so
comma army will get it how is the pretty
was hiking going
oh the Prius act lets go pretty well um
so we're also gonna another thing that
we're gonna push on is like that you saw
that keyboard thing right we don't know
why it happens but what we need to do is
we need to get out more build processes
and more tools to you guys so we have a
set of internal sk use for like
development tools we're gonna work on
making our development tools accessible
to anybody in the world the tools that
we're using here to develop everything
that you see we're gonna get the Neo s
build press is working so you'll
actually be able to fix the keyboard and
stuff yourself
maybe I think we'll leave an open source
you see the frame around the thing it's
called plus frame I think right now it's
closed source we gotta get this stuff
open sourced so we're gonna get more
stuff open sourced and more development
process available to anyone in the comma
army to to contribute so Camry Camry is
coming right coming is one of the cars
that is gonna be like easily ported
you'll be able to literally follow our
guide and do a port on the Camry the
2018 Camry like no we say no coding
experience required for the god I think
we can get it down to that point um
probably depends depends I think like
some variants for example like the
Cambria or like different dreams so can
be done with no guidance like no coding
experience if it's just a matter like
fingerprint differences it's very easy
so Civic guide well so the guide is
gonna be general and we can make one for
the Toyotas and the one for the one dose
is gonna be very very simpler I mean
yeah whoa
we're really gonna push on to our orders
and Lexuses this year um but no we can
yeah how do you think that will be maybe
we should do the same refactor I think
it's oh we're going to the 75
I mean there are few things that needs
to be changed in frontally just because
I interfaces api's are different
which year and model civic is best cvk
after 2016 he's supported you gotta have
found the sin saying and it can't be a
hatchback Civic correct Honda's are
really annoying because there's lots of
like different variants to them but you
know we open-source all this stuff I
think a lot of it is is it's too hard to
use right now for a lot of people we
need to make it we need to make it dumb
easy to use
you ever see the etherium documentation
that's where we need to go I mean you
know metallics building an army over
there to the Future says Army's cesari's
and you and I you and I we didn't look
into you in that yet but this something
so that's that's definitely doable
that's gonna require a programming
experience yeah if you're doing a port
to another Honda and Toyota there might
be no programming experience required if
you're doing a port to a different kind
of car you're gonna need programming
experience but to people out there have
managed to do it we need to proceed your
allies all of this stuff
so when these would be when these three
other paths will be available next
release next release so what do you
think the god will be done um ha I mean
before it depends when we do a fusion
work look at that if you have never seen
Network why would the hatchback not be
supported as totally different can
interfaces there is no easy access to
control longitudinal control yeah yeah
you'd have to you have to hack the radar
because a lot of the stuffs done down on
the radar but people are always asking
why is it not supported do you have a
Toyota Highlander you'll be able to
support that now yourself you'll be able
to follow our easy-to-use guide and
you'll be able to support it yourself
you need to make it so easy to use even
a baby can use it
we got a get plus frame open sourced you
gotta get all that stuff should be open
there's no reason it shouldn't be white
car Maya does not need movie light
vision cheap because we ever owned it's
called vision day we're using state of
the art machine learning from
crowd-sourced data from the whole Kama
army the real the real pawns in the Kama
army I mean I have an idea it's not even
an offensive title you guys if you're
out there collecting data with shiver I
think that makes you a pawn in the kama
army you're coming to the
[Music]
you come into the we can turn the scope
he's often you got to take that you get
a pawn in the Kama army if you come on
slack you start helping people out I
think that makes you a bishop alright I
gonna gonna take such a second take such
a sad Kings come up army maybe maybe
maybe enough chess pieces to have titles
right maybe maybe we'll work on real
military titles I'm gonna look up I'm
gonna look up military titles we're
gonna we're gonna work on some some real
some real titles for the Kama army
eventually you you you come and work
here you get to you get to lead the army
from from from actual headquarters guys
we're wearing this to win like like man
not like a team wins like an army wins
this is this isn't this isn't this isn't
football this is war
I mean and that's the where was I just
reading this cathartic Church of Christ
you religious yeah yeah no but that's
like it is IFRIC um when I was reading
that Steve Agee just quit Google and I
think I think that's how he really
described it who the describe just like
the competition between these companies
is not a football game it is war and
we're about ready to really really
ratchet up the game we have something
really big happening that I can't talk
about right now but it's really big you
guys will find out about it by the end
of the year if you thought the HD Maps
thing was big this is this is bigger
than the HTM thing I can't I can't talk
about it right now but it's gonna give
let's just say man remember that time
that uh the Europeans were losing World
War two and the Americans showed up it's
kind of like that
remember that time Dwight Tesla
struggles without Mobileye and we don't
why does Tesla struggle without mobile
right because there no no um no ep2
really that bad like is this thing
really better than AP - if that's true
then that is sad
I don't I don't know if I drove a car
once with a B - back in the day it is
this is certainly way better than it was
back in the day but by now they really
haven't managed to make it on par with
this that's that's that's surprising to
me why does Tesla start without the
Mobil ID chip because well it's
infrastructure really like mobile line
has tons and tons and tons of training
data that they were testing their stuff
on only recently has Tesla started
getting the data back from its fleet and
you have to build a lot of
infrastructure to use that data
meaningfully
oh are you worried that he's gonna be
out of there to a cop because like
they're gonna be looking down okay the
Fisher's you guys you guys look at--look
at Apple and Sony these companies have
spent millions and millions of dollars
on security and they couldn't stop me do
you really think the car companies can
stop me this I mean this is this is just
like look this is clearly just not
thought through the people who like say
this about Khamenei I like how are they
gonna lock and oh they're gonna put
encryption on it with keys oh wow while
encryption and keys were foiled you know
what actually the joke if they switch to
sums like more standard encryption and
more standard keys and more standard
ways of doing things it would actually
be easier for me like the whole
annoyance about hacking the Toyotas is
they have everything custom and
proprietary um its security to obscurity
it's a terrible idea for security but
people like me who are really good at
breaking like traditional security
systems that you'll find on like phones
or video game consoles that are actually
like good you know you just got it you
just got a muddle through the obscurity
though I'm getting way better attack in
the car stuff Dale well I'm also like
everything is going to the easier
direction like platform are becoming so
many some more common I called it to
your tester now much common to each
other than than before they share same
API is the same issues same messaging so
it's actually becoming easier
as a 16's he would say software is
eating the world every night and that's
what that's what this is right like when
you had like every you know every ever
like the Civic in the Accord using
different stuff why you got it you got
an API of five that I got a little
confused or even okay and this is with
the patch these well so the patch
doesn't affect the amount of thought
about foods if you don't touch anything
no but that was me holding it holding it
back yeah look at that that's with the
patch I think it's not even have to go
more yes
so what it's 500 what is it now on this
15 yeah yeah that overshoot and much so
the head of the Fiji is like that eights
so we can change the days before
shouting no no no this is certainly not
as bad as it like used to be I'm a
little I'm scared now what it would be
at five hundred I do think this is the
safety thing yeah no sludge yeah how are
we gonna like program that into the
Panda yeah I mean we yeah we need to
initialize doing it for
[Music]
yeah we already have the so we have the
Toyota that allows orders just like
changing yeah yeah so you'll just want
to give them like different safety mode
IDs
that's something else we should do I
mean that's gonna be the last step of
the boarding guide we got to talk about
safety you've got to talk about the
safety checks
we took a bet that's pretty guys
yeah it's happening it's happening but
it's not the big thing I have it this
you all seem to think a p2 sucks right
maybe 2 is 6 cameras
he sounds like more cameras are at the
solution right more cameras are
necessary but they're not that's a new
band question that's a new band the more
camera question is banned and the when
will my car be supported question who
should be responded to with a here's the
guide reporting it's not that we don't
think more cameras are necessary it's
that we don't think more cameras are at
all the hard part right you guys know
what the it's not like like if you're
like cargo cult engineering a cargo cult
engineering you had these people they
were on like a like a Pacific island and
the US would go there during World War
two the Japanese and these people were
like indigenous people they had like
sticks and rocks and I don't know if
they they had farming and I might have
had farming but like you know we're
talking real real real Stone Age stuff
here um they're these planes come out of
the sky US military planes with things
like MREs now that I've eaten MREs it's
pretty disgusting but if all your life
you've eaten like nuts and berries too
first even be exposed to any like sort
of the richness of modern food made
incredible things they had like things
like cans I mean even even even the most
dizziness people can see a can and can
appreciate it Wow like compare like like
a bucket to a coconut shell it's no
comparison right so these these absolute
Marvel's practically fell out of the sky
um the war ended in the plane stopped
coming so what do these people do well
they can really know how to make the
planes come back but they really wanted
the planes to come back to the planes
are great stuff on them so they built
planes now they very clearly didn't
build working planes they built wooden
things that looked like planes
this is what I mean by by cargo cult
engineering right and you see a lot of
this in the self-driving car world today
you'll see people who don't actually
know how to build a self-driving car
because that's a really hard problem
just like building a plan but building
something that looks like a self-driving
car is what a lot of these companies do
right just like kind of Wow put a bunch
of liners on it we'll put a bunch of
radars on it I'm not gonna call out the
worst offenders on this because some of
the MER okay people but the point is all
of the hard problems are solvable with a
single camera then shipping cameras is
an incredibly easy problem so that's why
that's a bad question
all right more questions
well
so it's a little it's a little jerky and
that's the same sort of thing is the
Prius yeah well it's different so I
think it's the same as therefore oh you
think this is the same as the rifle yes
the rav4 were that was my goodness
well answer therefore because there is a
lot more resistance like inside your car
yeah yeah
could the priests this one can kind of
really more can the priestly just be
caused by the weight of the car well no
because it's not no but that's what I
mean it's lighter than yeah but this is
way lighter than this way lighter it's
not bad it's like 2,800 pounds serious
torque yeah I mean I think it's the same
maxtor bigger meaning like you we want
you to meet that ideal
steering wheel it's more of the wheels
which band are you running y para great
pandas are still gonna work oh yeah so
we're gonna well - Evan those a pretty
soon does anyone remember the great
Panda contest if nobody remembers the
great panic on us we just won't give any
out nice Covey's
, how do you deal with parking all your
cash in the staff we stack them
vertically we have a elevator now we're
in the suburbs rose
can't we do this without disengagement
it's like you're just jerking why is
this yeah I mean because maldark a nice
day.this wants to change it changes yeah
but is this like a static friction
dynamic friction kind of problem like is
because of our ramp up it like winds up
and then gets to a point where it can
put real torque actually no I don't
think these one has much that problem
it's not like the Prius I think it's
really like there are far more I'm doing
that yeah I mean the models not doing
that no I do money's not yeah we will
take a look in Cabana see why it's like
this is all npc determining this too
right yeah yeah we can check their like
the commander sure yeah we're gonna
pushing a phone camera with a better
quality one you guys it's not the
sensors it's not the sensors none of the
problems in open pilot are caused by the
sensors best version coming next update
actually it's already it's not super
good he's gonna get a better birth time
oh you mean well maybe they were what
that means somebody answer cross their
honor all right I would step on the
brakes would the system stopped maybe
would I stop
yeah pay attention at all times guys
oh man okay I come up with army titles
what is your pecan Reiki how did you run
a care control work I was I studied at
the University then I worked a few years
Tesla and now , doing the same thing so
the coefficient of writing into can bust
my comedy I yeah so you can go to uh it
really depends okay so that's the thing
I normally hear a question like that and
I get frustrated and this is a personal
failing oh the phrasing was writing into
the campus like that so this is like how
I do interviews right like if I hear of
phrasing like that I get frustrated cuz
it's like writing into the can bus no
you like you like writing to a
television show to ask them why you
killed their your favorite character
right um so what do you want to write to
the can bus is the real question now
unfortunately there really aren't I
always say things like it's not my job
to educate you but that isn't true like
it is my job to educate you if we're
gonna win as an army imagine a general
that told his soldiers look guys we gave
to the gun it's not my job to educate
with that army win wars the army
wouldn't more so it is my job to educate
you and I have to think about really
what the best way to do this is so when
you're writing to the CANbus there's a
few reasons you might want to do this if
you're right into the canvas to lay open
pilot rights to cannabis there's this
isn't the right place to educate either
you know somebody I'd be so happy , army
who wants a promotion we don't the title
is yep who wants a promotion I'm gonna
explain some stuff now if you guys write
this up and like him you know come up
with the corroborating references and
put it on the wiki and then point people
to it that would be incredible oh okay
so open pilot replaces ECU's ECU's
communicate with each other over the
canvas and they send canned messages to
each other so when you tap in and you
use like a panda and cabana you're
seeing all the ECU is communicating with
each other you can unplug an ECU and
what you'll find is that some messages
stop being sent so what we do for the
Toyota is we unplug this ECU this ECU is
a camera and that lets us send the
command
to turn the wheel we also unplugged the
driving support ECU to send the
acceleration command but this is like
replacing ECU's a lot of the tutorials
you're gonna find on the internet for
sending to the can bus are using this
this is like ISO TP standard um with ISO
TP you can there's like an API which you
can use to talk to different ECU's this
is not how easy use talk to each other
so there's kind of two desperate uses of
the canvas there's the there's Bell like
this message is constantly always being
sent and then there's the hi can you
please tell me the VIN number of the car
okay here's the VIN number at the car um
so if you're interested in the first one
read open pilot if you're interested in
the second one read examples iso TP in
the panda in the panda library but yeah
we need to like have have resources like
that right and you know really fault
people like i think about how long it
took me to kind of learn this stuff i
mean it wasn't it was quick but like he
wasn't like I went somewhere I could
google it it was I had to figure things
out for three months right like that
people don't realize that like well the
OTB part on a lot of older cars is just
directly connected to the canvas of the
car in pin 6 and 14 on newer cars it's
sent through a gateway you see them like
on the Tesla you'll see nothing at all
even on Toyota's you don't really get
much
so to start to document that to surgery
was not like cars have different can
buses what a giraffe actually does how
many how many how many how many soldiers
out there know what a soldier comma army
and how many I mean y'all know what talk
about the can bus but more like yeah I
mean I think about like my initial
journey with the acura and by the way
guys like things have gotten a ton
easier than when I started when I
started I didn't know that like there
was that can boss on the OBD oh so yeah
yeah you have these these can gateways
right how many of you know what a
giraffe does its my question like how
many of you really understand why you
need a giraffe what that's doing and how
you might build a giraffe or another car
I know there's a bunch of you that do
but like how common knowledge is that
from the inside I don't really know I
need to mean wear some quick ketchup
what is that wire on the pillar that's
the power like a custom power to your
thumb fortunately don't apply custom
power up there to the camera so we ran a
wire just for come on here it's actually
isn't needed we can just like yeah we
can't disengage it yeah so it's not
needed actually up guys I disconnected
it we're gonna crash yeah which model is
erased race car these are 2017 the other
Corolla
what stop and go
sounds like someone who's hacking the
Toyotas they're gonna do a better job
all right definitely a shipful
experience the wheel could be a little
ass jerky okay and the brake there's
nothing we can do about that that's
always gonna be allowed and stop a
go-kart
but ya know wow these things have
serious torque do you think they did
like a torque injection functional
safety thing and they declared this to
be okay
no I think they have are there
limitations oh you mean like full talk
yeah the main thing is the torque rate I
don't really think it's like a full
torque but do you think they consider it
like anything you could send to the ECU
to be like okay and cue em well I'm sure
they have talked a the mutations we're
in the in the steering is you what they
do have in the steering your shield
which is well okay it's much higher than
what I would consider safe yeah exactly
me so right and obviously max torque is
this much torque is okay it's like 50
feet per second we limit this safety
even more in the Panda for the Toyotas
but cool scope ease thanks for joining
comma
army or company with ranks we're gonna
really this is gonna be the year and
guys something you're gonna get rich
like you think I'm getting some of you
were gonna get rich all right later bye
guys